

www.brianmont.com

**\** 2017073742

Philadelphia, PA

# **SKILLS**

BUSINESS SKILLS: Direct Sales, Business Development, Marketing, Public Speaking, Data Auditing, Strategy Development TECH SKILLS: Javascript, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, JQuery, Ruby, Rails, JSON, Git, CLI, React, Outlook, Powerpoint, Word, Excel

## **PROJECTS**

#### ANGULAR & REACT FRONT END METRICS

Nov 2016 to Dec 2016

- Refactored an AngularJS/JQuery music app I previously built to track user events.
- Added event listeners to track song plays, completions, and other user input.
- Implemented ReactJS rendering to display metric data in charts for easy review.

## **REACTJS TO-DO APPLICATION**

Dec 2016 to Jan 2017

- Built a functional to-do application for users to submit data via a form, which saves to a database and renders to the view.
- Implemented github OAuth, allowing users to access private data.
- Developed a React component which filters through saved data and checks for status and specific text.
- Refactored storage using Redux to simplify state mangement throughout all components.

WIKI APPLICATION Sep 2016 to Oct 2016

- Developed a Rails application where users have full CRUD capability over wiki pages.
- Configured gems to allow authentications, automate email confirmations, and address user roles.
- Managed and accessed database through Active Record, SQL, and rails migrations.

# **EMPLOYMENT**

## LD ENERGY CONSULTING

**Director of Operations** 

Rochelle Park, NJ Dec 2012, Dec 2012 to Current

- Review commodity contracts for more than 150 businesses to ensure clauses meet approval from all parties as well as compliance with state and federal laws.
- Create marketing plans based on market research and industry intelligence.
- Audit weekly usage and commission reports to ensure all payments and services are rendered in a timely manner.

**Account Executive** Jan 2012 to Current

- Booked more than \$3 million in gross sales in electricity and natural gas contracting.
- Negotiated forward prices in commodities to present the best strategies and products to fit each client's diverse needs.
- Led face to face presentations with high level decision makers and executive boards.

# **EDUCATION**

# The College of New Jersey

Major Business Administration 2011

Minor Finance 2011

#### Bloc

Front/Back End Web Development 2017

## SUMMARY

Over 5 years of commodity sales and consulting, I have gained experience and knowledge in dealing with constantly changing daily client needs. Organization and communication are keys to their success. Since January 2016 I have been learning new skills in UI/UX design and web development. It is my goal to attain a job where I can utilize my professional business experience and convey that through applications that will simplify daily processes for customers.